Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
I see.
So the Iscandarians had it.
Yes.
Mirenel sacrificed herself to tell me this.
So you are now the last of the Jirels.
You saved my life, Your Lordship.
Even if I am the last, I shall remain loyal to you.
Loyal, huh?
Planet Alteria — Nord Greater Province
So you ran, unable to deal with a single, native rebellion?
They surrounded the capital. There was nothing we could do!
Please, Director-General Gimleh!
Please use this fleet to protect the refugees that couldn't evacuate!
Let us burn this planet to the ground.
A planet that rebels against the Leader and the Empire
must not be allowed to exist in Great Garmillas territory.
That also goes for you, Governor.
That joke isn't funny...
I dislike jokes.
Now, play the melody of destruction!
Wave Motion Gun Control Room
This is the recoil brake for the gravity anchor.
Make sure it's fastened securely.
Huh? What are you doing here at this hour?
What... What is this?
Huh?
It's the Wave Motion Gun.
Weird, isn't it? Just leave it to the mechanics.
I want to see the craft I'm piloting for myself.
You have an attachment to it.
I don't like the way this looks.
Kodai?
You're still doing that?
Of course.
Next time, I'll show you I can pilot a fighter.
We left the Milky Way, but we're
encountering the enemy more often.
You won't get to—
I'm being serious.
So please take the time to teach me.
Ow.
Shinohara!
Did something happen with her?
A lot of things. But I guess you wouldn't know.
What is he talking about?
All crew to battle stations.
Again.
Repeat, all crew to battle stations.
Hurry! Hurry!
Scramble. Fighters, prepare to launch.
Catapult crew, prepare for launch.
Repeat, catapult crew, prepare for launch.
Two enemy cruisers.
I'll take over.
Thanks.
More force reconnaissance?
Ask the enemy.
All crew, stand by at battle stations.
Distance is 9,000. Speed unchanged.
Distance is now 8,000.
Enemy's turning around!
They keep calling us to battle stations!
We'll never get a chance to rest if we—
I guess I can understand her being upset.
She has stuff going on.
It will take time to get the OMCS back on line.
We'll need to find food and water, or our stores may run out.
But there are barely any systems in this area.
There's one.
The map Iscandar sent us says that a system lies four light years ahead.
Its name is Beemela.
Beemela...
Observation suggests the system's
fourth planet is likely an Earth-type.
That's great.
We've been on this tiny ship for too long.
Many of the crew are suffering from heavy stress.
I think it would be good for us to land.
Navigator Shima, your opinion?
It's fine, I guess.
It won't cause a problem with the schedule?
No, we'll be okay.
I see.
This is rough.
I'm gonna go nuts if we keep having to eat this every day.
I don't really feel like I've gotten any sleep.
Do you think Iscandar actually exists?
Jeez...
It's true!
Everyone's talking about a pretty girl's ghost that people keep seeing.
Hayashi, from navigation, saw it.
Really...
And they say that this ghost may be an alien.
What?
You look tired, so I was checking if you have a fever.
This isn't enough food.
The OMCS is down.
For now, it'll have to do.
Everyone's tired.
Food quality directly affects morale.
Are we really gonna be okay?
Oh, Misaki!
You haven't been running your radio lately... What's wrong?
Is the Wave Motion Gun
based on a specific solution of the Buchinsky Wave Motion formula?
You've done your homework.
This solution allows us to release part
of a miniaturized Calabi-Yau manifold.
Is the released energy proportional to
the space-time supersymmetry moduli?
No, it isn't directly correlated to the supersymmetry moduli.
At its core, it's a miniaturized superstring landscape.
Wouldn't that cause the superstring vacuum to dissipate?
The universe would be torn apart...
Yuria... Let's go over there.
The collapse of a Euclidean two-dimensional black hole?
I never realized.
I love Yuria's new hairstyle.
She changed her hair?
I'm certain... I'm sure of it!
The Wave Motion Gun... That weapon of mass destruction.
He must have made it.
The Leader is coming here, to Balun, for an inspection?
Admiral Ditz says that he's coming in secret.
Then we should prepare a reception!
If we wish to demonstrate our loyalty, we must first defeat the Yamato.
Our force recon has probably exhausted them.
Then it's time to strike!
Our recon battalion says that the Yamato has set course for the Beemela system.
That's right.
And this neutron star, Carell 163, lies between them and Beemela.
If they jump, Carell 163's gravity well will interfere,
causing them to Geschtam out at one of these five points.
We will attack then.
Deploy fleets at these five locations, and as soon as you see the Yamato, gather...
...and destroy them.
Zar Belk!
Stop! Running is useless.
Don't even think of the rebels as people. They are fleas.
If they resist, kill them.
This is the place.
I saw them run in here.
Prepare to enter.
This house is...
<Domel>
All ships are ready to launch.
All ships, launch!
Joint Staff Operations, Division 9.
That was where they proposed the Yamato Plan.
Joined the department on September 7th, '98.
Admiral Hijikata recommended her for the position.
Hijikata?
For the past year, since her parents died, Hijikata has been her guardian.
One year?
No siblings.
Her father was Undersecretary for Foreign Affairs, Naoyuki Mori.
Hijikata?
I can easily imagine him doing it...
Altering her records.
You aren't serious.
I am serious.
Professional intuition?
Something like that.
Why are you so interested in her?
Got a crush?
You don't need to know why.
Our next stop looks quite promising.
Then we'll be busy.
Just a word of advice... Stay away from the XO.
But even so, I'd like some insurance.
Leave it to me. I know where to go.
Hayashi? I've got that data input...
I brought you this.
Thanks.
How's the schedule looking?
Are we on track?
We'll be fine. We're making good progress.
You're a terrible liar.
I'm a counselor.
This voyage's success depends on you.
You're the most important person on this ship.
Navigation Officer...
May I have a moment?
Linking with system satellites. Opening Geschtam Gates to Balun.
Twenty gek until Gate opens.
Leader, our ship is now entering the Geschtam Gate.
Balun lies just beyond.
Problem in main engine.
Pressure is rising. At this rate, it will over-boost!
Stabilize it! Now!
The Leader is missing?
Why?
And you, Ditz!
Why are you the only one who knew this?
The Leader's whims are nothing new.
The marshal seems dissatisfied.
You're rather pleased, after putting down the rebellion on Alteria.
I did not put it down. I annihilated the planet.
The Imperial Guard goes too far.
That isn't true.
We cannot maintain peace in the Empire without fear.
It's true that rebellions have cropped up everywhere since the Yamato appeared.
But this just makes it worse...
Pure bloods are the only ones who matter.
We cannot trust the barbarians who do not have blue skin.
Men, this is no time for talk!
The Leader's Deusura has exploded.
Lord Desler has been assassinated!
Message from scout ship. They have sighted the Yamato.
Have the scouts provoke the Yamato. Force them into jumping.
No obstacles in our warp path.
Effects from the neutron star?
Our course will be affected.
All crew, prepare for warp.
Ship on our radar. Two enemy ships.
Approaching from our rear. Enemy speed is seven s-knots.
More force recon, right?
Damage to our port side.
Let's strike back.
No, go to warp.
But...
Without sufficient supplies, it would be folly to engage.
XO, the neutron star will affect our warp.
Try to compensate, then go to warp!
Report!
Neutron star is at ten o'clock.
So it did affect us.
Ships on our radar.
Enemy fleet off our bow.
Our rear, as well!
Multiple ships surrounding us!
So that's where the Yamato ended up emerging!
Right into our trap! Order all ships to rendezvous.
Launch fighters.
Wait.
No time to launch the Hayabusas.
They'd be hit while trying.
Captain!
Deploy Wave Motion Shield at maximum.
Charge them at combat speed 2. We'll break through!
Yes, sir.
But...
There's a Super-Dreadnought class ship in front of us!
We'll never make it through without taking risks!
Attack on our keel's shield.
Open torpedo tubes on bow!
Wave Motion Shield's deflection ability is decreasing.
If we keep taking hits, they'll penetrate it!
We'll strike their center. Concentrate fire to our front.
Open fire!
1604 has been hit.
Have them withdraw and switch position with the ship behind.
Wave Motion Shield is at critical point. Shield is dissipating!
The Yamato has broken through our front ships. It's approaching.
The Yamato is a fierce opponent.
Commander Domel!
Open all gunports! Destroy the Yamato!
Damn it!
Engine Room! What's wrong?
Gunport 1 is down!
Radar is gone.
Switch to inertial navigation!
Don't slow down!
We're only after one ship.
Keep going, and ram it if you must.
Right... Got it!
Evasive maneuvers!
Hold position! The Domelaze does not retreat!
Fire!
Engines to full!
Shake them off!
Battle stations!
There it is!
There's our prey!
Stay quiet, fool.
Second squad is in position.
This is checkmate.
Flying Squadron 3, strike from right side.
Commander Domel, a message from the home planet.
Later.
It's a class-one priority message from the Leader's Office.
The Leader's Office?
Secondary gunport 2, what's wrong?
Come in!
Engine output is dropping!
Secondary gunport 2, are you there?
Torpedoes! What are you doing? Lay down some fire!
An order to return home?
Why, Deputy Lord Hyss?
I almost have the Yamato...
No questions.
Withdraw the fleet, and return to the home planet.
This is a top-priority order. Understood?
Gunport 3, keep firing!
Damn it! Are we going to die here?
Don't be stupid!
Don't give up!
What?
Enemy ships are warping out.
All enemy ships have warped out.
What's going on?
They were this close... Why?
Something happened over there.
But what?
Episode 15
Point of No Return
No matter how steep or far the road is
I will not give up
Endless tears flowing down my cheek are not
A white flag of surrender
I go and become the wings of a loved one
Gather up the shattered dream
And take it to the end of the universe
Steady as she goes!
Row strongly
And hold your thoughts close to your chest
Steady as she goes!
Through your despair
A ray of light shines
The Yamato weighs anchor and rests its wounded body,
upon an Earth-like planet.
This is a place longed-for by those who will soon be extinct.
A conspiracy raises its head,
and we are asked what path we should take.
Next time: A Choice for the Future.
There are 287 days left before humanity is extinct.